# 大家好 今天我秤一下那個大肥狗 看一下有多重啦
Hi everyone! Today I'm gonna weigh the big fat dog, and see how heavy he is now.
# 應該差不多20斤啦
I think he should be almost 10 kilograms.
# 就它長得最大
He's always the biggest.
# 小狗
Puppies!
# 過來 過來 過來
Come here, come here, come here!
# 狗
Doggies!
# 嗯 這條最聽話它 秤一下你
Um! This is always the good boy. Let me weigh you.
# 坐穩
Sit well!
# 哎呀 好重
Aiya! He's so heavy!
# 坐下來
Sit down!
# 坐著嘛
Just sit down!
# 坐著就行啦
Sit down and relax!
# 你看
Look!
# 公斤秤
It's in kilograms.
# 9斤
Nine
# 9斤4兩
9.4 kilograms
# 你看
Look!
# 這個狗
This dog,
# 好乖的哦 這條
he's a very good boy, you know.
# 它 他的毛
His, his coat,
# 好多哇 這個毛
is really thick, his coat.
# 現在都19斤啦
He's now almost 10 kilograms.
# 它多少個月 2個月 2個月左右
How old is he? Two months, around two months
# 就長了19斤啦
And he's now almost 10 kilograms.
# 長得太快了哇 你
Don't you think that you're growing too fast?
# 很聽話的哦
He's a really good boy.
# 我一叫它 它就不走啦
He never runs away whenever I call him,
# 其它的一看到我來啦 全跑啦
while the others all run away whenever they see me.
# 乖 走
Good boy! Go!
# 下次天晴的時候給它去洗一下澡
I'll bathe him next time when it's sunny.
# 好髒呀 它的毛
His coat is so dirty now.
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 小狗
Puppy!
# 你看
Look!
# 夠高哦 現在
He's quite tall now.
# 現在 應該差不多 有半個半個我那麼高啦
I think, he's almost half, half as tall as me now.
# 幹嘛
What's up?
# 我又不會把你怎麼樣 你看 其它的狗看到我都跑
I won't do any harm on you. Look! Other dogs simply run away whenever I get close.
# 下次我們
Next time we'll,
# 把它們全部送人 就不 就不送你啦
we'll give them all out. But you, you'll be staying with us.
# 你我就不送
I'm not giving you out.
# 你那麼聽話
You're such a good boy.
# 小狗
Puppy!
# 看我一下
Look at me!
# 瞄我一眼哦
Just throw me a glance!
# 一直看著那邊
He's staring at that side..
# 它就是敢看我
But he dares not look at me.
# 哎呀 它一身 一身這個毛
Aya! His fur, his fur is all over the body.
# 它不動的
He's not moving at all.
# 很乖的這個狗
He's a very good boy.
# 其它狗不乖哦 就你最乖
The other puppies are all naughty. You're the only good boy.
# 小狗
Puppy!
# 是不是就你最乖 (註︰"The best boy"之類的說法太奇怪，所以一直避用)
Are you the only good boy?
# 到這裡好不好玩
Do you like staying here?
# 看一下牙齒
Let me see your teeth.
# 不刷牙牙齒都那麼白
How can your teeth be that white? You never brush your teeth.
# 不刷牙的牙齒這麼白
How can you keep the teeth so white without brushing them?